- Who's got the scene ?
- Massey and Crutchfield are working it.
Norris is on his way to the morgue.
He'll beat the bodies there.
He's getting the full treatment, boss.
We're good there.
Just one witness so far.
You know what that means.
Right now it's all BNBG.
It's Andy Kraw's
big adventure.
Mayor's office already called twice,
worried sick about the man.
You're kidding me.
That's a whole lotta
campaign contributions
sitting on the back of that ambo.
So what's the scene say ?
Two shooters. Shotgun, semiauto.
One vic is a West Side soldier
with a pretty healthy sheet
the other is a major player
in Daniel's wiretap case.
So a hit.
Drug related.
With a big time developer
in the middle ?
What's the fit ?
Second vic, Russell Bell
owner and co-developer
of this here.
And other downtown
real estate.
Well propertied man,
he was.
But you were aware that Russell Bell
was regarded as a major
narcotic violator.
Well, how do you think
he made his money ?
I didn't inquire.
You never got a look
at either of the gunmen.
I told you. I saw only the one of them.
He was black
big, I thought,
with a large weapon.
BNBG.
Big negro, big gun.
Two more
like it upstairs.
Yeah.
Have ballistics rush comparisons.
Drug-relateds for the last six months.
I caught him, Bunk.
On the wire. I caught him.
He doesn't
fuckin'know it.
Mission Accomplished
Boxing, yeah.
I know
you loved that.
Ugh, I hated it.
I hated watching it.
Yeah,
I know you did.
So you're
doing good, huh ?
Day to day, I am.
'Cause I was thinking
maybe...
I'm proud of you, Dennis.
Be well.
Shut that
fuckin'door.
Man, fuck it.
I'm ready for this shit.
These niggers are snappin'on us.
You see ?
Do you believe this fucking shit ?
Some shit like this woulda never
happened with the old Barksdale.
Yo, Slim, man.
Say the motherfuckin'word.
Shit is on.
'Sup, B ?
You a'ight ?
We gonna bounce back
on the motherfucker, no question.
Bounce back on who ?
Marlo, boss.
Oh, he gonna fall.
Marlo, Marlo ain't got
shit to do with it.
Marlo couldn't
get String like that.
String died'cause of some other shit.
What ?
He died because
of some other shit, nigger.
I couldn't fix it.
I tried.
That nigger String was
right about this shit, man.
That nigger was right.
Fuck Marlo. Fuck this fucking war.
All this beef over
a couple of fuckin'corners.
Don't matter who did
what to who at this point.
Fact is, we went to war
and now there ain't no going back.
I mean, shit
it's what war is, you know.
Once you in it, you in it.
If it's a lie
then we fight on that lie
but we gotta fight.
Got this out of his pocket.
I got no idea.
It's a cell chip from a phone.
What elsedid you get off him ?
200 cash, set of keys, license.
President Street address ?
I got Landsman bangin'out
a warrant for the place.
Fuck the politics for a minute.
What if the man happens to be right ?
Legalizing drugs ?
Crime is down in his district and
people on that side of town,
they're okay with it.
Look, if you don't exist,
what happens here ?
If there's no Tommy Carcetti
in this thing,
what's likely to happen ?
The mayor and Burrell,
they shut this thing down.
I figure the Mayor's
trying to find a way
to shuit down to make it look like
it was an enforcement plan
in case it goes public
otherwise he'd have
moved to end it already.
Makes sense.
But no matter what
Colvin's little experiment
is finished.
Come on, Tommy.
They dealt you a winning hand
and you're acting like you
forgot how to play.
Mr. Mayor, call it legalization
and my office can't live with it.
Agreed.
No one can.
But harm reduction.
That could sell provided there's a
reduction in the crime rate.
Harm reduction.
Sounds good.
Steven, what if we were
able to suggest
limiting our
street level enforcement
we were concentrating our resources
on high-level traffickers.
How would that play ?
Well, if I could show off that kind
of casework, yeah, maybe.
But they've been doing
street rips for so long now
I don't think
a high level exists.
What if we were able to say
that no major traffickers
were allowed in the free zone--
That the major violators
were still being targeted, huh ?
Are you suggesting
some kind of admissions
criteria for the zones ?
How would that work ?
I don't know that it would.
I'm just saying that for
the sake of public perception.
Come on, people,
work with me on this thing.
Fucked up, ain't it ?
Marlo need to get his ass
dropped, him and all his crew.
They gonna fall.
You'll see.
All right, let me know.
That's the word
on the wire, anyway.
Every mention puts it
on Marlo Stanfield's crew
which means the war's
gonna ratchet up, no question.
Where's Jimmy ?
He went with Bunk Moreland
to rifle Stringer's spot downtown.
- How'd he take it ?
- Like Stringer was kin.
- Yeah ?
- Bushy Top
- need to pull your coat up.
- Hey, what's up, Major ?
I got somethin'for y'all.
Mount Vernon Square in about an hour.
I'm there.
This is Stringer's ?
Yeah.
Who in fuck was I chasing ?
What's done is done.
Gay ass gangsters.
Please.
I took it for as long as I could.
Let's go, man.
Let's go.
It being your town, I trust you
to do it proper.
You off today, boss ?
Every day, at this point.
I told 'em over at COMSTAT
about my little experiment.
Bosses went crazy, huh ?
Anyway, that's why I called you.
That there is a wartime lay-up
for your man Barksdale.
My sources tell me the man's there
most of the time
with a lot of muscle :
sawed-offs, semiautos, Mac-11s.
Whole lot of good shit
if you hit it right.
- That's a hell of a tip.
- Shit.
That right there might be
the last bit of police work
in a long and storied career.
I'll talk to you, Bushy Top.
Which one is Ali ?
In the white trunks, boy.
- Damn, he look young.
- He was.
This the Patterson fight
right here. Old school.
Who Patterson ?
He soft.
Ali whippin'his ass.
He was a champ too.
Look, any man still standing
at the end of a round
you can't call him soft.
That's a rule, all right ?
From Stringer's place downtown.
B and B shit, college papers,
real estate stuff.
There's no phone extension
in the place, just these.
Cell phone chips.'Bout 100 of them.
So that's why he wasn't
taking any phones
from our man Bernard, huh ?
Stringer had his own phone
he just changed the number every
time he changed the chip.
Shamrock too, probably, with
whatever phone he used to call Bell.
Cautious man.
Yes and no.
Have a look in here.
All different manufacturers.
Before Stringer Bell got aced
he went out of his way to put in
his good friend Avon Barksdale.
That's a Barksdale safe house.
Where'd you get this ?
Colvin.
- Calls to the Western.
- Where's Daniels ?
He's got this thing downtown.
It's for his wife.
You should raise him.
It's not enough
to make up for Stringer.
It'll do for now.
Because the neighborhoods
and the residents
in this district are among
the poorest in our city.
And it is these residents
who most need
a strong voice at City Hall.
Time has come for a change.
And I believe I can
bring about that change
by providing a strong voice
for the new 11th District
if you will do me the honor--
It's kind of cool, the lieutenant's wife
running for office, you know.
Well, as you just heard,
West Baltimore City
Council woman Eunetta Perkins
is going to have her hands full
in next September's
Democratic finals.
Stringer Bell.
Damn.
Who could have got to him ?
I mean, if it wasn't y'all on it.
You know Avon's gonna
put it on you, right ?
Shit, let him take it
on my jacket.
Don't make me no never mind.
I'm thinkin'it might be what
you call one of them good problems.
Yeah.
I heard Colvin's
in deep shit downtown.
Looking at this right here
he might not be the only one.
Anything comes up,
I'm on the radio.
My man, my man, my man.
Yo, you think I could get like $5 ?
- I need like $5 to get on the bus.
- I look like a tourist to you ?
- Man, I swear to God.
- Lookin'like that
walking into
an open-air drug market
why the hell would
I think you'll spend my $5
on bus fare ?
Shit,'cause I already
got my blast, man.
All night you been drinking
like your ass is candy.
That's shameful shit.
12-gauge pumpkin balls.
Last time I saw that kind of load
was the Pimlico double
and I fuckin'know that motherfucker
was in the middle of that mess.
And if I remember your boy
he had no love
for the Barksdale people.
Execution style, that don't play
like Omar Little.
Besides, the word on our wire
is that Marlo's people did Stringer.
- Marlo Stanfield ?
- The heir apparent.
This city's going to hell, man.
We're gonna push past 300 murders
before New Year's.
Shit is fucked.
Oh, hey, Cheryl.
No ? My guess is she's, uh,
picking up a prisoner.
Yeah, I spoke to her
about ten minutes ago.
Yeah, well, they make you
check your stuff.
Cell phone, money, weapon.
Well, she'll call
when she gets the message.
Not at all.
I need more, Jimmy.
More !
Motherfucker.
I'm tired, Bunk.
Let's go.
I heard the vanguard met.
Heard they voted to have a
civilian review board look at it.
It wasn't unanimous. And there were
people there speaking for you.
I heard that too.
So six out of ten black officers
think I'm just an asshole racist.
On the other hand
four out of ten
think you're just an asshole.
It's an administrative charge.
You can fight it and win
if you want.
Failure to properly identify myself
as a police officer.
Sounds like what I was guilty of
most of my career, actually.
I'm not sure
I was supposed to be a police.
Not really.
What were ya supposed to be, huh ?
This is from Major Colvin's CI ?
What's the corroboration ?
Well, the source knew that Barksdale
had a waterfront condo in his own name
gave the accurate location,
and title info
down to deed of transfer.
Well, that's good, but it puts him on
the legitimate side of things.
What corroboration is there
for illegal activities ?
Sorry I'm late.
I had to stop in at a friend.
The source knew that Barksdale
was shot last month
wounded in the shoulder.
- Emergency room ?
- No, no hospital reports.
We're gonna need better.
Either Colvin goes back to the CI
or we sit on this address for a while.
- we can see.
- Well, fuck it, then.
Let's name the source.
Put him right in the affidavit.
- It's Colvin's call, isn't it ?
- It's Stringer Bell.
Lester figured it out from the DNRs.
Bell was snitching out Barksdale.
- You're sure of this ?
- Maybe that explains the murder.
What's in the wire ?
Loose talk about how
it was Marlo's people
but nothing past rumor.
With Bell gone, Barksdale might
have to come down a notch
to oversee the day to day, and
maybe that puts him in contact
with some of our
monitored cell phones.
If he's as cautious
as Stringer, maybe not.
My guess is Barksdale
never touches a cell phone.
Safe house might be our best shot.
All right.
We stay on the wires until
this batch of burners
goes dead, hoping
we have Barksdale
but meanwhile, we get a warrant
for that safe house
and wait on him there.
Thanks for the cover last night.
This is Greggs, Major Case Unit.
Who's the shift leader ?
Holy Christ.
- They're all over it, Commissioner.
- Right
That was Foxtrot.
The cameras have found our
little shit pile.
Your fuckin'councilman
took his sweet time, didn't he ?
Everyone's a critic.
If this doesn't go, what line
of work are you gonna try next ?
We're here in West Baltimore--
For more than a month, police
from Baltimore's Western District.
It's just an outrageous development.
It's something I never thought I'd see
from this or any other administration.
Frankly, this is one of the
reasons we need a change
in leadership in this city.
Did the Mayor know ?
What about the Police Commissioner ?
These are questions for the
Mayor and Police Commissioner.
These are central issues
of crime and safety.
The Royce administration
is simply bankrupt.
You still gonna announce
for mayor next month ?
Standing here today
looking at this ?
I can't see I can do anything
but put it out there right now.
All I can tell you is that
for more than four weeks now
the Baltimore Police
Department surrendered
portions of the police district
to the drug trade
and the Council was not informed.
Fuck me. I fuckin' had this story
all to myself a week ago.
Police officers for weeks
have turned a blind eye...
What the fuck was I thinking ?
..sanctioning open-air
drug markets.
'Scuse us.
...in the so called free zones,
drug dealers routinely ply...
Mr. Mayor,
Commissioner Burrell is here.
Tell the Commissioner the Mayor
will be with him shortly.
And young children run
the streets alone.
The inhabitants of what
has come to be known
as Hampsterdam have little
to say for the camera.
But channel 5 has learned
that the police were...
Yeah ?
What are you seein'?
Coupla people in and out.
No sign of Barksdale, though.
It's quiet here too.
Okay.
Need to look at the back.
Our friend Carcetti's gonna
run wild with this.
And from the sound of things,
Gray is gonna run with him.
Tony Gray thinks he's gonna
get my chair behind this bullshit
We're throwin'you out
of the boat, Ervin.
This shit is on you alone.
Not necessarily.
Not if I talk about how
we were under pressure
to keep the crime down
to juke the stats
district by district...
You never said that.
About how Colvin under pressure,
lost his way
about how I came to you
weeks ago...
- Days ago.
- Weeks ago
to tell you what he had
done and to assure you that
we were on top of the situation
that Colvin would be relieved
and his plan aborted.
You lyin'motherfucker.
But you heard about the drop
in Colvin's felony rate
and you sent me packing.
Brought in your liberal-ass
do-gooders to seriously consider
this horseshit
while Colvin's
mistake grew and grew.
My hands were tied, Mr. Mayor
my department thwarted.
I was a prisoner
of the goddamn politicians.
Or...
I leave your office right now
willing to say a lot less than that.
I put what I can
on crazy-ass Bunny Colvin
and I take the hit.
And if Carcetti or Gray holds hearings
I'm the wall between them and you.
In which case, I am your commissioner
for the full five-year term.
Unit one to unit two.
- Unit two standing by.
- Deal's made.
Unit two to sector three,
move on the Winchester Homes.
Ten-four. We're moving.
Unit two to sector two.
Move on the Koppers plant.
Roger that.
Over the top, gentlemen.
'Bout fucking time.
Man, g outaigo re-up.
- Where Tuckie at ?
- I don't know.
- Yo, where Tuckie at, man ?
- He rolled out.
- He said the police comin'.
- D'oh.
- Here they come. Let's roll.
Hold it right there
White jacket !
Stop right there ! Stop !
Freeze ! Police, don't move !
Outstanding, red team.
Oustanding.
Give you a case
of beer for that one.
Son, this nigga Stringer Bell, man
was beggin'Chris, yo, for real.
Like know what I mean ?
Diggin'in his pockets,
talkin' 'bout how much cheese
he gonna give us, I mean,
if we just let him walk.
My man Chris holler,
"Man, bitch, you gonna die."
This nigga just dropped
to his fuckin' knees like
a little cocksucker,
man, start cryin'.
That shit was worse
than fuckin' pathetic.
- Yo, that's Marlo.
- Get on yo'burner, man.
- Got a line on him.
- The number one ? Where at ?
Tall man says
to tell y'all to soldier up.
They up at the rim shop.
- Boss, you okay ?
- What you want ?
Slim said they got
their eye on Marlo.
I'm just sayin', you know,
all the boys, they all waitin'on you.
Go ahead, man.
I'm behind you.
What else you need
from us, Deputy ?
City Hall wants
the bulldozers through here
at dawnand then fencing
all around the site.
Winchester Homes
and the Koppers plant as well.
We got it.
Come tomorrow,
the television reporters
get nothing they can
stand in front of.
'Scuse me, Deputy,
sir, we found a body.
Any trauma ?
Can't tell for sure
with all the rat bites.
Take him to OCME
in a jail wagon.
I don't want the fuckin'
reporters seeing any ambos.
Shit.
He just landed. Him plus one.
Got it. Sit tight.
That makes how many ?
Including Barksdale, Sydnor
counted ten in
and one comin'out,
so that's ten at least.
2301 to KGA.
Go ahead, 2301.
We need QRT to meet us at our 20
for a search and seizure.
Location has multiple suspects
and may contain automatic weapons.
Ten-four.
Word travels fast, huh ?
Shit.
Burrell called Johns Hopkins
personally this morning.
Dragged your name into the gutter.
Johns Hopkins doesn't
need the notoriety.
The chief academic officer of a
major research university
doesn't want to hear
that some new hire
makes up the rules
as he goes along.
Yeah, Colvin.
COMSTAT tomorrow.
I'm up.
Y'all taking a door ?
Where's tactical ?
I called for QRT.
You ain't heard ?
They're a little busy tonight
tearin'down Colvin's fuck up.
With all that goin'on,
you're lucky you even got us.
- Who he hittin' on this ?
- Avon Barksdale and crew.
I fuckin' told you he was out.
Did i fuckin' tell you ?
I fuckin' told her.
For more than four weeks,
the Baltimore Police Department...
By tomorrow, the story goes national
and Washington reacts.
Save the best
questions for Tony Gray.
He needs to shine
even more than you.
I can't believe
he wants us to knock.
Well, you can' flush
guns, now, can you ?
Well, fuck that.
What if they open up on us ?
These guys are
at war with another crew.
We go chargin'in there,
chances are we will get lit up.
Yo, B.
Sham sayin'that Charles
sayin'they still up at the rim shop.
Marlo, his boy Chris,
and Vinson, they still eatin'
but the rest of the muscle,
they rolled out.
Police !
No.
Not the police.
- Narco's out back too.
- Shit.
Let us in !
We know you're in there.
Open the door,
you fucking cocksuckers !
Fucked up, man.
Y'all ask me
y'all ugly ass niggers
shouldn't be in here
fucking around
with all these guns and shit
Open it.
Come on, Avon. Enough with this shit.
Open the fucking door.
Open the fucking door,
you cocksuckers.
Police !
- Search warrant !
- I'm clean, man.
Open the fucking door.
Get down !
Face that shit tight. Greggs.
I'm opening up.
That'd be mine.
In fact,
all that's mine.
You got a law degree ?
Take him.
You fall on the parole violation.
No matter whatever else happens
you do every day of
what's left of your seven
without seeing a jury.
Maybe even conspiracy to murder.
We take this federal, see if we can
get you ten to life... no parole.
Whatever.
Shit, you only do two days no how.
- That's the day you go in.
- And the day you come out.
Yeah, well, here's the warrant.
You read it slow.
In between them two days,
give you something to think on.
Damn.
Missed our shot.
Roll, man.
You bend over for us,
or I swear to God
I will spend what's
left of my career
shitting on every last
supervisor in your district.
From shift commanders down
to sector sergeants, not one of them
will have any rank at all if we
hear so much as a bark out of you.
Look, my people saw this as a
tactical deployment only.
The responsibility is mine alone.
Well, you won't fall alone
unless you're willing to fall exactly
as we want you to.
After COMSTAT,
you go to retirement services
and drop papers, going out
at a lieutenant's grade
That's right, you're busted back.
We can't take your EOD away
but you're not going out
on a major's pay.
I can retire before you bust me.
I got vacation time
enough to make my 30.
Fuck your vacation time.
You're out today, at the lower grade.
That's against the goddamn contract.
What part of bend over
didn't you understand ?
Avon locked up ?
With most of his muscle, yeah.
Good day to get back out
on them corners, ain't it ?
Make some money.
You bet.
It's not just the 17 millions
in federal funding
for Baltimore law enforcement
that you've jeopardized.
Take off another 200 million of federal
money in your operating budget
another 75 in capital expenditures,
plus untold millions in pass-through
federal dollars from Annapolis.
All told, we're talking about
half a billion a year that Baltimore
will be doing without.
Furthermore, the U.S. Attorney here
will use all the resources
of the Justice Department
to interdict and destroy
any attempt to establish
a geographic entity
where drugs are legal.
Washington should know that
what happened in West Baltimore
in no way reflects the policies
of my administration.
That was an aberration,
Mr. Talmadge.
The work of one
misguided police official.
We understand your concerns
but for the deputy drug czar
to take the time out
to drive 30 miles north
to deliver that message,
hardly necessary.
Rest assured.
What up, G ?
Where the older ones at ?
Marlo got his package back out.
Fire Burrell.
This nonsense began in his shop
without him knowing it.
Fire the man and move on.
Odell, I respect your opinion.
But right now
Tony Gray, Carcetti maneuvering
now is not the time.
We get past the primary, then I'll drive
a stake in his heart.
But right now
I need him where he is
for no other reason than to
well, to take the hit
for this thing right here.
But I tell you what
I'm gonna do, though.
I'm gonna shine on that new girl
you like in the 11th.
Give her a spot on the ticket.
Cut Eunetta loose.
Eunetta's had her day.
I respect the fact that
you stood by me, Odell.
I respect loyalty.
And did so without properly
informing his superior officers
and without regard to the criminal
statutes he was sworn to enforce
thereby disgracing himself
and his command.
Is any of that subject
to any contradiction
or argument whatsoever,
Major Colvin ?
No, sir.
No argument at all, Bunny ?
Not much you can say, is there ?
Not to real police.
- Get on with it,motherfu--
- 'Scuse me, major ?
Is the admin lieutenant present ?
Major Colvin is relieved of duty.
You are now the acting commander
of the Western District.
- Hey, Bunk.
- Hey, Freamon.
- Who is that ? Crutchfield ?
- Naw, Norris.
Sleeping on a stakeout.
Damn, Bernard, didn't I tell
you about these guys ?
Yeah, that's everyone
we heard on the wire.
McNulty's over there in number
one with Pearlman.
Why don't you say hey ?
You got to be
the stupidest motherfucker
that I've ever gone out with.
I can't wait to go to jail.
What ? What you say ?
What the fuck did you say, Bernard ?
Hey, Donald.
- You heard the tapes.
- Look, he came to me
and said we could sell drugs
if we move down to Vincent Street
and that's where I moved my crew.
And you know I did because you the one
that popped me with the G-pack
on my way to the spot,
and let me go, remember ?
You were selling drugs
in Major Colvin's free zone ?
- You can prove that.
- Ask him. He know.
This must be one of them
contrapment things.
You mean entrapment.
Kid's got a point.
19 in bracelets
from Barksdale on down.
Another eight wanted on warrants.
Any way you can tie your case
to this mess with Colvin ?
Make it like what he was
doing led to your thing ?
I don't see it.
Well, it's good work
nonetheless, Major Daniels.
Call came in from the Mayor's office
half hour ago
approving your promotion.
And now with Colvin,
there's a new vacancy.
- What about my wife ?
- What about her ?
The Mayor. Eunetta's seat.
- Why would the Mayor...
- Good police work maybe.
Not everything is politics.
Hey, I'll take two. Western alumni.
All right, you got it.
Major.
I heard.
How's your family take it ?
Lolita done dropped herself
30 pounds and got herself
a real estate license
so I guess she's fixin'to leave me.
I just wanted you to know
that last tip you gave me
was a winner.
Yeah, I heard.
That's good work.
Also, I don't know if you know,
Stringer Bell was shot to death
two days ago.
So anyway,
I put his name on the paper
to tighten the PC.
I figured what the fuck
once he's aced, right ?
You always did cut
them corners, didn't you ?
Seems like you cut a few
yourself, Major.
However it ends,
you're good police.
I just did what I did.
It felt right.
I'm fine with that.
I don't understand.
Drink your wine.
You and me in public.
- But your wife.
- She wins without me.
On the Mayor's ticket, she wins.
And you make major ?
I think she was waiting for this day
more than I ever was.
And now she's not here.
No.
She's not.
From out of nowhere, huh ?
Nowhere is right.
Why me ?
I guess you don't live right.
- Kari, what was that ?
- Nothing.
- What broke ?
- Nothing, Mama.
So...
Yeah.
You just drive over here.
I did.
Why tonight ? What happened ?
I was in my old district tonight
which is where I used
to feel pretty good, I think.
I wasn't so angry
when I was there anyway.
I don't know, someone said
something, I guess
and, uhit doesn't make sense.
I guess I finished something today.
A case ?
More than that.
It's like everything
I poured into a glass
came out the bottom
and I just kept on pouring.
Like the thing had
a hole in it, you know.
Things that make me right
for this job
maybe they're the same things
that make me wrong
for everything else.
Do you want to come inside
for a drink ?
Not tonight.
But if it's not too late,
I wouldn't mind
meeting your kids.
Major Colvin misled his officers.
They thought that his initiative
was a tactical deployment
to entrap narcotics traffickers.
There was no mention whatsoever
of the initiative to
any superior officer.
And for five weeks, all evidence
of what he was doing managed to elude
the entire command staff.
Are you kidding, Commissioner ?
I take full responsibility
and indeed, after I first learned
of the matter
I informed the Mayor, and together
we moved immediately
to relieve Major Colvin
I'm under the impression that
this administration
gave serious consideration
with Colvin's initiative.
No, sir.
Major Colvin informed you of his effort
at a COMSTAT meeting
more than a week ago.
His free zones stayed up
for six days after that.
That's my responsibility, Councilman.
We needed the time to conclude
an ongoing investigation
by the Major Crime Unit,
a wiretap case
that would have been disrupted
Correct, Mayor Royce was aware
of the pending case
and allowed us to delay
our response accordingly.
But the Mayor was unequivocal
in his opposition
to what Major Colvin did.
What we have here, I'm afraid,
is nothing more complicated
than a solitary police commander
who, under great pressure
proved to be amoral, incompetent,
and unfit for command.
No.
It's about more than that.
This is more important
than who knew what when
or who falls on his sword
or whether someone
can use this disaster
to make a political point or two.
Mr. Chairman--
We can forgive Major Colvin who,
out of his frustration
and despair, found himself
condoning something which
can't possibly be condoned.
We can do that much.
But, gentlemen, what we can't forgive,
what I can't forgive ever
is how we...
you, me, this administration,
all of us
how we turned away from those streets
in West Baltimore. The poor, the sick
the swollen underclass of our city
trapped in the wreckage of neighborhoods
which were once so prized.
Communities which
we've failed to defend,
which we have surrendered
to the horrors of the drug trade.
And if this disaster demands anything
of us as a city
it demands that we say enough.
Enough to the despair which makes
policemen even think about surrender.
Enough to the fact that
these neighborhoods are not saved
or are beyond the saving.
Enough to this administration's
indecisiveness and lethargy
to the garbage
which goes uncollected
the lots and row houses
which stay vacant
the addicts who go untreated
the working men and women
who every day
are denied a chance
at economic freedom.
Enough to the crime,
which every day
chokes more and more
of the life from our city.
And...
the thing of it is, if we don't
take responsibility and step up
not just for the mistakes
and the miscues
but for whether or not we're gonna
win this battle for our streets
if that doesn't happen
we're gonna lose these neighborhoods
and ultimately this city forever.
If we don't have the courage
and the conviction to fight this war
they way it should be fought
the way it needs to be fought,
using every weapon
that we can possibly muster,
if that doesn't happen
well, then we're staring at defeat.
And that defeat
should not and cannot
and will not be forgiven.
It was a good case
I'm not denying that
but I need to trust my people.
Unless you can give
your word, there's no way--
That's more than fair.
Thanks.
But it's better for me
if I do something else.
Detective.
It's not you, it's me.
- But where--
- The western, I think.
Western feels like home.
You showed something today.
Just felt like it needed to be said.
Sounds like you're
running for something.
Eunetta.
Been a while.
Thought y'all was in training.
So what time you want us to be
there tomorrow, coach ?
3:30 would be good.
- Hope to see you all then.
- A'right.
What the fuck y'all
standing around for ?
Man, get to work.
That's a seed.
Yeah.
What do you see right here?
It's bulk metal. 10¢ a pound.
Here.
Aluminum.
Right you are. 30¢ a pound
no problem.
in these modern times a man
gotta keep one eye on the ground
pick up what he find, feel me ?
There's money to be made
if you know where to look.
I hope you listenin','cause
I'm tryin'to school you here.
Yeah, you don't want to know.
You see, You think you brown,
but you still green.
How ya doin'?
That's somethin', huh ?
It's like they took a big
eraserand rubbed across it.
Yaeh !
Yeah, but before a dope
fiend come down here
cop a little somethin',
ain't nary a soul hassle him.
Hoppers and police,
they just let him be.
Was a good thing, huh ?
I'm just sayin'.
You probly don't know,
but it's rough out there, baby.
Cops be back bangin'on you.
Hoppers be messin' with you.
Thank you.
Aw, shit.
That's a dime here.
That's a seed.
Come on, boy.
Transcript par Raceman
Sous-titres par la Wired Team :
Occeane et El Uploador.
www.thewire-france.com
www.forom.com